• Software Engineer •

xingh.neha.17it2012@gmail.com

• In LinkedIn Profile

ABOUT ME

As a Software Engineer, I have extensively worked on ASP .NET Core Web Application development following SOLID Principles. I have designed secure RESTful APIs in C#, meeting industry standards and automated complex business processes with BPMN - powered flowcharts, significantly improving workflow efficiency and reducing manual efforts by 30%. Enjoys infusing the latest technology to simplify processes, much like how I've curated an engaging experience for you to explore my profile via My Own Portfolio website (Click Me!). Specializing in Camunda BPMN and ASP .NET Core, I'm proficient in C# and JavaScript.

EXPERIENCE

GEP Solutions Private Limited, Navi Mumbai

Software Engineer

Jan 2023 - Nov 2023

- Technologies worked on: C#, ASP .NET Core, Elastic Search, Camunda, Postman.
- During this period, I took the charge to work extensively on camunda workflows and rule engine .
- I was entrusted with the critical task of addressing PROD Blockers during HyperCare mode of project, where I had the opportunity to lead and collaborate with my colleagues on various new features and bugs. With the team support we used to close 70% of the issues raised in just 2-3 days where everyday almost 10 new bugs or features used to appear.
- One notable accomplishment during this time was optimizing the time utilization for extensive data correction of about 30,000 documents under immense pressure and personally corrected 2000 orders by making automation scripts in Postman for the team. The script reduced the Manual efforts to correct the data by 90% and reduced human errors and time wastage by 99%.
- Implemented various validation processes using the Rule Engine on v2 Nexxe project which was very precise and compact yet easy to read and understand, ensuring data integrity and accuracy throughout the system.

Associate Software Engineer

Sept 2021 - Jan 2023

- Technologies worked on: C#, Elastic Search, Camunda, Cypress.
- Worked Majorly on building APIs and Camunda workflow changes.
- Also wrote few SQL queries to make changes into Mongo DB and fetch Data from tables.
- Did Elastic search Data type mappings to insert Data into ES seamlessly via kibana.
- My role has involved working on numerous stories and resolving bugs to introduce new features, consistently contributing to the growth and functionality of the product.

Dimensionless Technologies, Navi Mumbai

April 2021 - Sept 2021

Full stack Intern

- Technologies worked on: Django, React.Js, Javascript, Postman, Sphinx, OpenCV.
- Worked on backend as well as frontend in Web application development for Machine learning projects.
- For frontend worked on creating forms and main application page using React.js
- For backend worked on creating methods and logics using Django for scanning products in machine and then returning the name of object scanned in real time to the display.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2021 • B.E. Degree In Information Technology From, Ramrao Adik Institute Of Technology, Mumbai university. CGPA - 6.75

2015 - 2017 • High School (Science Stream)

From, Pace Junior Science College, Maharashtra State Board - 71%

2005 - 2015 • **School**

From, St. Joseph High School, CBSE 10th boards - 91%

HOBBIES

Learning New Technologies, Automations, Reading Non-fictional Books, Games, Travelling, Cooking.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, JavaScript, Python.

 $\textbf{Web Development} : ASP. NET \ Core, \ Camunda, \ HTML, \ CSS$

React Js.

Database: LINQ, Entity Framework, SQL Server, MongoDB, Elastic Search.

Development Tools: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code,

JIRA, Postman.

Development Practices: Design Patterns, Object-Oriented

Programming (OOP), Solid Principles.

Communication & Collaboration: Team management.

Testing & Debugging: Debugging, Unit-testing, Console-

Debugging.

Ownership: End-to-end implementation.